So before you joined
this program, your journey
to hit your goals
probably looks a little
bit like this, where
you were trying to
grow and make money,
but the results were
kind of unexpected and
not particularly consistent. But
now you've paid me,
naturally, you're expecting this
to happen, where suddenly
everything just clicks into
place and you hit
all your goals and
YouTube just starts working
magically. But I have
to reset those expectations
because most people who
come into this go
backwards before they go
forwards, meaning your views
and sales can drop
or slow down. But
that is intentional and
it's part of the
process, as you're going
to discover at the
end of this phase.
The thing is, not
getting instant results after
putting in a ton
of work I'm going
to get you to
do, that is going
to wreck your motivation,
even when you know
this. So in this
video, I'm going to
do two things. I'm
going to show you
exactly what to expect
so that you don't
panic and quit. And
then I'm going to
give you the most
powerful tool pretty much
every successful entrepreneur I've
ever met lives by,
which is to make
a profit. And this
really does separate the
winners from the losers.
All right. So this
is quickly run you
through what's about to
happen to you so
that you can react
in ways that will
get you results. So
this is the staircase
of pain. This bottom
access here, this represents
time. And then the
flat part of the
stair here is called
the pain zone. And
then these big jump
ups, that's called the
joy zone. To hit
your goal, all you
need to do is
get up the staircase
to the top. And
right now you are
here in a joy
zone because you're riding
on this emotional, high
of signing up to
this. And you're really
starting to pick up
on the fact that
Ed has put a
huge amount of work
into this. But then
in the next 24
to 48 hours, that
emotion, excitement is going
to vanish and you're
going to realize, oh
my gosh, this is
so much more work
than I thought. And
you're going to get
overwhelmed. And then after
30 days of not
posting a single video,
even though you feel
like you've been working
so flipping hard, you
are back here in
the pain zone and
you're going to question
everything. And you're going
to want to quit.
But then you're going
to shoot up again
into the joy zone.
When you finally release
your first batch of
videos until the first
one's going to flop.
The second one, you're
almost going to be
embarrassed by how bad
the views are. And
then the third is
going to do the
same. As a result,
you're going to start
blaming others. You're going
to have this real
frustration towards me. And
you're going to start
thinking, well, it doesn't
work for me clearly.
And it works for
Ed. But then one
of your videos is
going to blow past
all of your others.
And you're going to
go, Ed was right.
Stick to the plan.
This works people. And
you're back in the
joy zone until your
next video, which is
your worst performing of
all time. And you
want to quit again.
What you have to
realize is the pain
versus joy. It never
ends. You're going to
be happy with a
thousand views. Then you're
going to hit 5
,000. Then you're going
to be angry with
4 ,000 a week
later. You're going to
have sales drop, products
flop. And then months
where you're looking at
Ferraris or Chanel handbags
thinking, this joy is
never going to end.
So what I'm trying
to make clear here
is 99 % of
the time we are
on the pain zone,
even though we are
continually getting closer to
our goal. But why
does it have to
be like this, Ed?
Why can't it just
be easy? Well, let
me show you. And
then I'm going to
give you the most
powerful mindset shift that
is the difference between
the winners and losers
in this game. So
have you ever seen
the incredible Hulk? Before
he became the Hulk,
Bruce Banner was this
brilliant scientist, but he
wasn't capable of saving
the world because he
didn't have the strength
or the resilience. But
one day he gets
hit with these gamma
rays and it hurts.
You can see here,
his body's breaking. And
he's screaming in pain
as every cell gets
torn apart and rebuilt.
But that pain is
what turns him into
the Hulk. So this
is why you have
to spend 99 %
of your time in
the pain zone. Because
in order to become
a person who's capable
of achieving the things
they want to, you
have to break yourself
to remake yourself. That
means you have to
learn new things, which
is hard. You're going
to have to try
things that don't work
out, which will feel
like a waste of
time. And you're going
to have to push
yourself and practice until
you have the skills
that will enable you
to achieve your goals.
And you're going to
have to achieve those
goals, which is always
painful because none of
that is easy. But
there is one powerful
way you can make
this 10 times easier
on yourself. And that
is to remove the
emotion on this. So
when you win or
lose, you don't ever
feel any pain. But
how do you do
that? Well, let me
give you the mindset
shift for success. Only
the winners in this
game know about. And
it works like this.
So I want you
to imagine you are
a two year old
and there is a
lion in your room.
What do you do
if your natural instinct
is run away? We've
got some mindset work
to do on you.
Because a two year
old doesn't think, what
if that thing eats
me? They think, wow,
what is this giant
fluffy thing? And then
they walk towards it
and give it a
stroke, curious to see
what might happen. And
this is how kids
learn. They act, then
see what happens, then
they adapt. They don't
fear the outcome. They're
just very curious about
it. And childlike curiosity
is exactly the mindset
you need for this
program to work and
for YouTube to work
and growing a business
to work. Because the
moment you stop asking,
what if I fail?
And you start asking.
I wonder what will
happen if I take
that action? You become
unstoppable because my whole
system is built on
a curiosity premise called
fail as fast as
you can. And it
works like this. Step
one, you create a
minimum viable version of
something that could be
a new video style,
a sales page, an
email sequence. It doesn't
have to be perfect.
It just needs to
exist. And we call
this your MVP. Step
two, you drive traffic
to the MVP. You
post the video. You
promote the sales page.
You send that email.
And then step three,
you just try and
learn one lesson about
why what happened happened.
So you ask, why
did this video blow
up? Why did sales
drop? Why did nobody
click? Because if you
can just find one
lesson, we can then
action it in the
next MVP and increase
our chances of success.
The mindset shift you
have to get to
grips with is even
if you blow up
a video, if you
can't figure out why
it got that result,
you have actually failed.
But if a video
flopped. And you figure
out why you win
because you take that
lesson into the next
one, meaning you're less
likely to do it
again. And this is
how we grow. And
that is why this
system works. Because when
you repeat this loop
enough times, you eliminate
weak ideas and end
up with only powerful
high impact moves. So
let me show you
what this looks like
on YouTube, because this
is going to be
the cause of most
pain for you. So
let's say you're starting
from scratch on your
channel. It's still small.
This chart here shows
your videos in batches
of four. And what
happens? A red video
means it's underperforming or
below average. And a
yellow means it performed
above average and grew
the channel. Now here's
what you need to
understand. On average, three
in 10 videos from
world class creators, I'm
talking about the whole
Moses, the Alib Dals,
the big channels will
perform above average. So
in batch one, you're
going to post your
first four videos in
my new system and
they are going to
all perform below average
and you're going to
panic. But that is
just phase one doing
its job. The whole
idea is to practice
the system. Because you're
not close to being
a master of it
yet. And then batch
two, you're going to
try again. And this
time it's going to
be a similar thing.
And you're going to
start shouting, I hate
it. Batch three, look,
we finally have a
yellow one. And because
we used the fail
as fast as you
can system, you know
exactly why it worked.
And then batch four,
you just repeat that
lesson and it works
again if the lesson
was right. And now
we've got our first
repeatable format. Then in
batch five to six.
Look, there's some reds,
but another yellow appears.
And now we've got
two data back plays
that we can repeat.
So you keep going
and you eventually discover
three to four repeatable
formats or angles that
consistently outperform your baseline.
And that's all we
do. But here's what
you need to understand.
At least 70 %
of your videos will
always be red. Even
world -class creators like
Homozy or Abdaal, ones
with massive teams and
tons of credibility, they
only ever see three
out of 10 of
their videos perform above
average. So if you're
expecting every video to
beat the last, you're
just setting yourself up
to fail. But what
happens is as we
get more yellows, the
channel's average baseline views
per video increases. So
in my month's time,
you're going to look
back and you're cursing
only getting 10 ,000
views in a week.
Whereas when you started,
you would have been
over the moon with
200. But also have
a look at this
chart again. You see
that over time, the
yellow starts showing up
more often as we
fail as fast as
we can. Which is
not luck. That is
just the result of
disciplined testing, measuring, and
repeating what worked. So
yes, I am going
to blast you with
gamma rays. And yes,
it's going to hurt
a lot. And yes,
you're going to go
backwards before you go
forward. But that is
how you become the
Hulk you were destined
to be. And if
you can stick through
this painful transformation, even
when it sucks, which
I guarantee it will,
you're going to come
out the other side
of a channel and
a business that is
built to win. So
now let's move on
to the next video
where we're going to
start breaking you and
rebuilding you into someone
who can actually hit
those goals. This video
is sponsored by Six
T quantities, part of
or is Joes because
of the subtitles Tim
just對對icals Sir, there were